The principles of Aikido can be applied to daily life in many different situations.
It can be applied in your family with your spouse, with your kids.
It can be applied at work with an irate boss or co-worker.
It could be an upset driver.
It could be somebody with road rage.
We are going to demonstrate a couple of different techniques to emphasize the principles and why don't we just take a peek.
For example if there is somebody coming at you with road rage it is probably best not to block, not to stop them with your car but just to let them go right by and with Aikido it looks something like this.
I'll show you.
So that is one way, you can just let them go right by.
If you need to deal with the situation a little bit more it might look something like this.
In that, that last technique, as Phil comes in and attacks we enter and we face the same direction.
We can see exactly what they are seeing.
We can get a little different perspective.
If we think that we need to deal with the situation a little bit more directly we can just go off the attack immediately.
As he attacks just turn and go right in.
Everything is blending and harmonizing.
Some can be a little more direct.
Others can just not connect with that energy.
If it is negative energy or anger or frustration you don't need to deal with it.
There are many different ways as you can see to deal with each individual situation and Aikido principles will help you deal with that in daily life.